Claudio Atilano

claudio@primaltcg.com | (786) 663-0320 | http://claudioatilano.com

Summary

I am a Software Engineer with 5 years of experience. I can identify the need for a solution and communicate with users to create their desired solution. I am self-disciplined in creating applications under a given timeline and focused on constant product iterations.

Skills

- MongoDB
- Express.js
- ReactJS
- React Native
- Node.js
- Oracle

- SQL
- Javascript
- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- Linux/Unix

- Java
- AWS Services
- Git
- RESTful APIs
- GraphQL
- Playwright/Jest

Work Experience

Rhenus Logistics

January 2021 - Present

Front End Developer

Designed and developed a scalable multi-tenant warehouse management solution for third party logistics providers and resellers or manufacturers.

- Lead developer for client interfaces using ReactJS and React Native.
- Created front end CICD pipeline with Github Actions. Designed scalable applications using AWS AppConfig.
- Built fast iterable applications to demo to prospective businesses with the Director of Software Development.

Beacon Hill Consulting Group

July 2020 - January 2021

React Developer

Developed an upgraded warehouse management system using ReactJS and created a warehouse management React Native app that was used by Zebra scanners.

- Was solely responsible for the development of client interfaces using ReactJS and React Native.
- Developed using GraphQL, used Typescript knowledge, used AWS Cognito and Amplify services.
- Developed 25 automated end-to-end application tests developed with Jest and Playwright and Github Actions

NextEra Energy

March 2019 - June 2020

Associate IT Programmer Analyst

Developed and designed a scalable data driven customer communication platform for NextEra Energy's newly acquired utility company, Gulf Power Company. This platform was programmed with Java using the spring framework and Javascript for their user interfaces.

- Led a team of 2 onsite developers and 3 offshore Java developers with Agile methodologies and tracked developments through JIRA. Trained new developers on the Java codebase.
- Developed a batch email sending module using AWS SES and Java to send over 10,000 email bills to customers.
- Upgraded 2 user interfaces that were using iQuery and Javascript to ReactJS.

Metamesh Inc.

Jan 2018 - March 2019

Co-Founder, Full Stack Software Developer

Founded company dedicated to helping people sell products with affiliate marketing incentives through a progressive web application.

- Programmed a RESTful API using Node.js, MongoDB and Stripe for a social e-commerce application.
- Designed and developed an elegant responsive front end using ReactJS, HTML, CSS and Javascript that can be downloaded as a progressive web app.

Projects

Naruto CCG Community Application

Jan 2019 - Present

https://app.narutoccg.com

I identified the need for a community app for the Naruto CCG community. I developed and deployed an Android and iOS application with React Native that has 120 daily active users, 1,000 weekly active users and 33,000 registered users worldwide.

- Created a RESTful API for card data using Express.js Node.js and MongoDB and deployed it on an AWS Linux EC2 instance
- Implemented a realtime chat feature using web sockets with push notifications for community members to communicate with each other across mobile clients with React Native.

Education

Bachelor of Arts, Physics

May 2017

Cum Laude

Florida International University

Miami, FL